<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gray is colorful </title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gray is colorful </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rei Sayag</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>testthis</title>
      <link>/2020/02/09/2020-02-09-testthis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/09/2020-02-09-testthis/</guid>
      <description>Test this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difference-in-differences for causal inference </title>
      <link>/2020/01/21/2020-01-21-difference-in-difference-for-causal-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/21/2020-01-21-difference-in-difference-for-causal-inference/</guid>
      <description>## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;dplyr&amp;#39; ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:stats&amp;#39;: ## ## filter, lag ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:base&amp;#39;: ## ## intersect, setdiff, setequal, union ## Warning: attributes are not identical across measure variables; ## they will be dropped df &amp;lt;- read.csv(&amp;#39;card_and_krueger_1994.csv&amp;#39;, header = TRUE) fit &amp;lt;- lm(employment ~ time + new_jersey + time:new_jersey, data = df) summary(fit) ## ## Call: ## lm(formula = employment ~ time + new_jersey + time:new_jersey, ## data = df) ## ## Residuals: ## Min 1Q Median 3Q Max ## -10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using pre expriment data for better results</title>
      <link>/2019/12/20/2019-12-20-using-pre-expriment-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/20/2019-12-20-using-pre-expriment-data/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>test</title>
      <link>/2019/11/07/2019-11-07-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/07/2019-11-07-test/</guid>
      <description>#Test Hello world</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framing matters</title>
      <link>/2019/01/17/2019-01-17-framing-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/17/2019-01-17-framing-matters/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on January 13, 2016 at grayiscolorful.blogspot.com
Would you rather contribute to a charity with the goal of saving children’s lives or to a charity that aims at preventing the deaths of children? Both charities’ goals are identical, but many would prefer to contribute to the second charity rather to the first one. The first charity’s goal is framed as making a gain while the second is framed as preventing a loss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Republicans and Netanyahu are helping Obama’s Iran deal</title>
      <link>/2019/01/17/2019-01-17-how-the-republicans-and-netanyahu-are-helping-obama-s-iran-deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/17/2019-01-17-how-the-republicans-and-netanyahu-are-helping-obama-s-iran-deal/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on May 3, 2015 at grayiscolorful.blogspot.com
The Book of Genesis describes God’s decision to punish Sodom and Gomorrah for their wickedness. God tells Abraham about his intention, turning Abraham into an advocate for the two cities. In his new role, Abraham bargains with God over the threshold of evidence required to find Sodom and Gomorrah guilty. Step by step, Abraham succeeds in decreasing the number of righteous people required to demonstrate there is a reasonable doubt that the cities are guilty of wickedness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I, We or no one: Who wrote that paper? (Economists edition)</title>
      <link>/2019/01/17/2019-01-17-i-we-or-no-one-who-wrote-that-paper-economists-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/17/2019-01-17-i-we-or-no-one-who-wrote-that-paper-economists-edition/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on October 27, 2014 at grayiscolorful.blogspot.com
Have you ever written a academic paper as a single author? Did you ever struggle how to find the correct wording to describe the paper? What do most authors do? Have that changed over time? What do experienced authors do?
Whether it was for a course assignment or a peer-reviewed article, at some point you were probably told that neutral and passive writing is preferred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I, We, or no one: Does gender matter?</title>
      <link>/2019/01/17/2019-01-17-i-we-or-no-one-does-gender-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/17/2019-01-17-i-we-or-no-one-does-gender-matter/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on February 9, 2016 at grayiscolorful.blogspot.com
How do writers refer to their own single author work when writing about it? Do they use singular pronouns (e.g. ‘I predict the existence of a 9th planet’), more participative plural pronouns (e.g. ‘Our model fits the observed data’), or avoid pronouns all together (e.g. ‘The paper examines tool usage by parrots’)? Is there a difference between male and female authors?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s the economy stupid: Why can (and should) Europe welcome many more refugees</title>
      <link>/2019/01/17/2019-01-17-it-s-the-economy-stupid-why-can-and-should-europe-welcome-many-more-refugees/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/17/2019-01-17-it-s-the-economy-stupid-why-can-and-should-europe-welcome-many-more-refugees/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on September 16, 2015 at grayiscolorful.blogspot.com
How many refugees can European countries reasonably take? How many should they take? Although some on the European right believe the answer is none, most agree that some refugees must be accepted. To look at the burden refugees place on host countries, some (Vox, The Economist) look at the number of refugees taken by countries relatively to those countries’ population size. This makes intuitive sense – for example, the more populated a country is the more people work per refugee, the lower is the burden of integration on individual communities, and the more secure people are that their country’s culture is not altered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case for optimism in a crazy world</title>
      <link>/2019/01/17/2019-01-17-the-case-for-optimism-in-a-crazy-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/17/2019-01-17-the-case-for-optimism-in-a-crazy-world/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on Septmeber 11, 2014 at grayiscolorful.blogspot.com
Lately, it seems like the world is increasingly going bananas. The Russian-Ukrainian conflict is bringing back dark echos from the past, ultra-extreme Muslim organizations rise in the middle-east, China is flexing its muscles in south-east Asia, and Europe’s economy is sliding back. Nonetheless, if I were asked whether the world will be a better place in 30 years (or 20, or 50, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which are the fastest (and slowest) running countries in the world?</title>
      <link>/2019/01/17/2019-01-17-which-are-the-fastest-and-slowest-running-countries-in-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/17/2019-01-17-which-are-the-fastest-and-slowest-running-countries-in-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on March 3, 2016 at grayiscolorful.blogspot.com
As running becomes more and more popular around the world, the need to rank countries by the speed of their runners is clearly needed. Why should I care you ask? It’s a good point you’re making I’d retort, but we seem to like ranking of all sorts of things so why not? We rank countries by feelings of love, Cities by bike-friendliness, and even professions by right swipes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics and wars -- on the number of civilian casualties in Gaza</title>
      <link>/2019/01/16/2019-01-16-statistics-and-wars-on-the-number-of-civilian-casualties-in-gaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/16/2019-01-16-statistics-and-wars-on-the-number-of-civilian-casualties-in-gaza/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on August 7, 2014 at grayiscolorful.blogspot.com
A cautionary note: this may be a bit of a sensitive topic to have for a first blog post.
During the last couple of days I encountered a couple of analyses questioning the official figures given in the media about Palestinian civilian casualties during the period of operation Protective Edge in Gaza. Currently, the UN puts the death toll at a minimum of 72% and Gazan groups at 82% and 84%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/2015/07/23/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/23/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact Aenean ipsum justo, semper eu nisl ut, pretium tincidunt sem. Praesent et diam sit amet lacus lobortis dictum a id lacus. Quisque hendrerit sit amet turpis eu varius. Ut id lorem ac felis ultrices tincidunt. Pellentesque consequat arcu ac fringilla imperdiet. Phasellus pellentesque, sapien non pulvinar blandit, sapien ante aliquet felis, vel porttitor sapien ante in lacus. Fusce non urna aliquet, malesuada nibh vel, luctus urna. Phasellus ut lacus molestie, varius purus quis, malesuada lorem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My awesome project</title>
      <link>/project/my-awesome-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/my-awesome-project/</guid>
      <description>About project Aenean ipsum justo, semper eu nisl ut, pretium tincidunt sem. Praesent et diam sit amet lacus lobortis dictum a id lacus. Quisque hendrerit sit amet turpis eu varius. Ut id lorem ac felis ultrices tincidunt. Pellentesque consequat arcu ac fringilla imperdiet. Phasellus pellentesque, sapien non pulvinar blandit, sapien ante aliquet felis, vel porttitor sapien ante in lacus. Fusce non urna aliquet, malesuada nibh vel, luctus urna. Phasellus ut lacus molestie, varius purus quis, malesuada lorem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>About the blog This blog deals with with topics that I happen to find interesting, puzzling or just quaint. My usual approach to such matters is to use data, economic theory and some common sense.
About me The name is Rei Sayag. Living in Amsterdam and loving it. Dabbled in Economics and Behavioral research in my mischievous youth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>